ulster.ac.uk 2012-12-26

# Cookies and Privacy - University of Ulster

**Cookies & Privacy **

* * *

The University of Ulster is committed to preserving your privacy. Please read the following information on cookies and privacy to understand how we use and protect the information obtained from those visiting and using our website. 

  * Information that we collect about you
  * Use of your information
  * Disclosure of your information
  * Security of payment transactions
  * Data Protection
  * Storage of your information
  * IP addresses and cookies: The information we collect
    * Cookies and how to control and delete them
    * Analytics, information services web applications, embedded content and sharing cookies
    * Google Analytics
    * University of Ulster Information Services Web Applications
    * Sharing our content
    * Share This
    * Add This
    * Twitter widget
    * Facebook
    * YouTube
    * Links to external sites
    * How to manage your cookies
  * Security
  * Changes to this Privacy Statement
  * Third Party Links
  * Contact us

* * *

**Information that we collect from you**

We collect information about you: 

  * From your usage of the website and any other information you post via our website, e-mail or otherwise send to us. 
  * When you provide us with your personal details (e.g. name, contact details, e-mail address etc) when registering with us or submitting an enquiry via the website; 
  * When you respond to occasional surveys which we may ask you to complete for research and website testing purposes. 

Top

* * *

**Use of your information**

We use your information: 

  * To ensure that our website content is presented in the most effective manner to you and for your computer; 
  * For analysis so that we can administer, support and improve and develop the website; 
  * To enable us to supply you with the goods, services and information that you have requested; 
  * To notify you about changes to our service. 

We may contact you by post, telephone or fax as well as by e-mail and SMS. If you change your mind about being contacted in the future by any of these means then please let us know so that we may update our records. 

Top

* * *

**Disclosure of your information**

The University of Ulster recognises the importance of protecting the privacy of all information provided by users of our web site and except as set out in this policy or as required by law, your personal data will not be provided to any third party without your prior written consent. 

Your personal information may be disclosed to other businesses within the University, and to reputable third party contractors engaged by the University in order to perform a variety of functions such as processing orders, assisting with promotions or providing technical services for our websites. We require all third parties to fully comply with all applicable UK Data Protection and consumer legislation.

Unless required or permitted to do so by law, we will not otherwise share, sell or distribute any of the information you provide to us without your consent. 

The University of Ulster reserves the right to engage with reputable third party contractors who operate outside the European Economic Area (EEA). All personal data / information will be transferred securely using adequate and appropriate protection to ensure compliance with the eight Data Protection Principles. 

Top

* * *

**Security of payment transactions**

Any payment transactions undertaken on our website will be encrypted for your security. Some areas of our website use third-party software facilities for payment transactions such as Realex Payments. Please note that data storage on Realex Payments systems and the communication between Realex Payments and the worldwide banking networks is regularly audited by the banking authorities to ensure a secure transaction environment. This ensures that secure transactional processes we offer via Realex Payments adhere to global security and data protection standards.

Top

* * *

**Data Protection**

The University of Ulster is committed to protecting the rights of individuals in accordance with the provisions of the Data Protection Act 1998. We are committed to the eight Data Protection Principles contained within the Act. These principles represent best standards of practice with respect to the transmission, retention and disposal of personal data. All staff, students and others who process or use any personal data must comply with these Principles. These state that personal data must: 

  1. Be processed fairly and lawfully; 
  2. Be obtained only for the purposes specified and shall only be processed for those purposes; 
  3. Be adequate, relevant and not excessive for the purpose for which they are processed; 
  4. Be accurate and kept up to date; 
  5. Be kept for no longer than is necessary; 
  6. Be processed in accordance with the rights of data subjects under the 1998 Data Protection Act; 
  7. Be protected against unauthorised processing of personal data and against accidental loss or destruction to personal data; 
  8. Not be transferred outside the European Economic Area without adequate protection. 

Our Data Protection Policy [can be downloaded](http://plangov.ulster.ac.uk/governance/pdfs/data_protection_policy.pdf) as a PDF. 

Top

* * *

**Storage of your information**

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. You must not share your username and password with anyone. 

The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the website. Ant transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use the strict procedures and security features embedded within our Data Protection Policy to try to protect against unauthorised access.

Top

* * *

**IP addresses and cookies: The information we collect**

We collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type. This information is collated to provide statistical data concerning browsing actions and patterns. It will never identify any individual. We use this information to inform our decision making regarding improvements to our website, for system administration and to report aggregate information to third parties where necessary.

Top

* * *

**Cookies and how to control and delete them**

The University of Ulster uses cookies to make our sites as useful as possible. Cookies are small text files that we place in your browser to track usage of our sites. These cookies do not tell us who you are.

No information can ever be traced to an individual person, and the cookie only relates to activity on our websites. The information cannot be used for marketing on an individual basis.

Our cookies do not collect additional information about you and do not in any way compromise the security of your computer. For information on how to disable and delete cookies from your computer on a wide variety of browsers please visit [All About Cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). This site also provides more general information about cookies. 

If you wish to restrict or block the cookies which are set by University of Ulster websites this can be done through your browser settings. For information on how to remove cookies from the browser of your mobile phone please refer to your handset manual. If you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our website. 

Unless you have adjusted your browser security setting to refuse cookies the University of Ulster will issue cookies automatically.

The University of Ulster uses suppliers who also set cookies on the University's websites on our behalf in order to deliver the services that they provide. Further information about the cookies and how to opt-out is provided below.

Top

* * *

**Analytics, information services web applications, embedded content and sharing cookies**

**Google Analytics**

Analytics cookies (provided by Google, Inc.) are used to allow the University of Ulster to understand which pages you are currently accessing on the website. It allows us to enhance your user experience by adding new features and functionality based on what you require from our site.

We use “Google Analytics”, which is a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc., to help us analyse how our website is being used. In doing so information about your use of our website, including your IP address, may be transmitted to, and stored by, Google. This information will be subject to Google's Privacy Policy.

See [Google's Privacy Policy](http://www.google.co.uk/policies/privacy/)

**What if I opt out?**  
Your user experience will not change at all. However, the University of Ulster will be unable to understand your use of the website.

The University of Ulster also uses Google Analytics to anonymously track and analyse users and user behaviour. This requires the use of cookies.

**Name** | **Content** | **Purpose** | **Expires**  
---|---|---|---  
_utma | Randomly generated number | Identifying unique visitors | 2 years  
_utmb | Randomly generated number | Determining visitor session | 30 mins  
_utmc | Randomly generated number | Determining visitor session | Session  
_utmz | Randomly generated number + info on how the site was reached (e.g. directly or via a link, organic search or paid search) | Tracking traffic sources & navigation | 6 months  

[Further information about how Google Analytics uses cookies](https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies).

Top

* * *

**University of Ulster Information Services Web Applications**

All of our web based applications require users to engage and provide information in order to gain access to content and to track users in the application, for example Outlook Web Access for staff email. These systems need to store information about these interactions so they can provide the service and in some instances they use cookies to do this.  All users that need to authenticate to University of Ulster Information Services web based applications have already signed the Acceptable Use Code of Practice which involves monitoring on and within the web application/service (as detailed in the University’s [IT Monitoring Policy](https://secure.ulster.ac.uk/isd/policies/Policies/Approved/IT%20Monitoring%20Policy%2020111108.pdf) and [IT Monitoring Code of Practice](https://secure.ulster.ac.uk/isd/policies/Policies/Approved/IT%20Monitoring%20Code%20of%20Practice%20v.1.pdf)).

Further policy information: [ISD Policies](http://ulster.ac.uk/isd/about-us/policies)

Our Cookies – [http://portal.ulster.ac.uk](http://portal.ulster.ac.uk/)

**Name** | **Use** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
UserAgentId | Luminis | Session  
fos.web.server | Luminis | Session  
fos.secure.web.server | Luminis (Secure) | Session  
runId | Luminis | Session  
userid | Luminis | Session  
X-Mapping-djjgfhcn | Luminis | Session  
JSESSIONID | J Session Id | Session  
UUVistaTicket | Athens | Session  
70385458C06E42E45B0B1D392B80101AathensCheck | Athens | Session  
sctSession | Luminis | Session  
  
Our Cookies – [http://staffdev.ulster.ac.uk](http://staffdev.ulster.ac.uk/)

**Name** | **Use** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
exp_last_visit | Expression Engine | 1 Year  
exp_last_activity | Expression Engine | 1 Year  
exp_tracker | Expression Engine | Session  
  
Our Cookies – [http://ssb.ulster.ac.uk](http://ssb.ulster.ac.uk/)

**Name** | **Use** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
accessibility |   | Session  
TESTID |   | Session  
SESSID | Session id | Session  
  
Our Cookies – [http://blogs.ulster.ac.uk](http://blogs.ulster.ac.uk/)

**Name** | **Use** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
X-Mapping-nfejpjia | zeus | Session  
PHPSESSID | Session id | Session  
  
Our Cookies – [http://cms.ws.ulster.ac.uk](http://cms.ws.ulster.ac.uk/)

**Name** | **Use** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
PHPSESSID | Session id | Session  
  
Our Cookies – [http://wiki.ulster.ac.uk](http://wiki.ulster.ac.uk/) 

**Name** | **Use** | **Expires**  
---|---|---  
JSESSIONID | J Session Id | Session  
BIGipServerWiki_Pool | wiki | Session  
  
Top

* * *

**Sharing our content**

Certain parts of the University of Ulster website carry embedded 'like' or 'share' buttons to enable users of the site to easily share pages with their friends through a number of popular social networks. These sites may set a cookie when you are also logged in to their service. University of Ulster does not control the dissemination of these cookies and you should check the relevant third party website for more information about these.

Top

* * *

**Share This**

Share This is a social sharing plugin. This is used to allow users to share an interesting article which has been found on the University of Ulster website.

**What if I opt out?**  
If you opt out, you will no longer see the Share this button on the University of Ulster site.

**Name** | **Content** | **Purpose** | **Expires**  
---|---|---|---  
_stid | Randomly generated number | Social bookmarking: ShareThis widget | 1 year  
_uset | True or False | Social bookmarking: ShareThis widget | 1 year  
UID | Randomly generated number | Social bookmarking: ShareThis widget | 2 years  
UIDR | Randomly generated number | Social bookmarking: ShareThis widget | 2 years  
  
The [Share This privacy policy](http://sharethis.com/privacy).

Top

* * *

**Add This**

Add This is a social sharing plugin. This is used to allow users to share an interesting article which has been found on the University of Ulster website.

**What if I opt out?**  
If you opt out, you will no longer see the "Add This" button on the University of Ulster site.

**Name** | **Content** | **Purpose** | **Expires**  
---|---|---|---  
uid | Randomly generated number | Social bookmarking: AddThis widget | 2 years  
uvc | User id and login time tracking | Social bookmarking: AddThis widget | 2 years  
uit | True or False | Social bookmarking: AddThis widget | 1 day  
psc | True or False | Social bookmarking: AddThis widget | 2 years  
_atuvc | User id and login time tracking | Social bookmarking: AddThis widget | 1 minute  
_atshc | Page URL and share count | Social bookmarking: AddThis widget | Session  
ssh | Randomly generated number | Social bookmarking: AddThis widget | Session  
sshs | Service share history | Social bookmarking: AddThis widget | Session  
ssc | Service share history | Social bookmarking: AddThis widget | Session  
  
[The Add This privacy policy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy#.T7z3hEVYt8E). 

Top

* * *

**Twitter widget**

Twitter has a widget which shows the most recent tweets on the University of Ulster website.

**What if I opt out?**  
The Twitter widget will not load on the site, and you will not see the recent tweets.

[The Twitter privacy policy](https://twitter.com/privacy). 

Top

* * *

**Facebook**

Facebook has a range of options which allow you to limit who can see your personal information; just taking a few minutes to change your settings should protect you from identity fraud or other unwanted attention.

[The Facebook data use policy](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/). 

Top

* * *

**YouTube**

The University of Ulster sometimes embeds content from websites such as YouTube within its sites. As a result, when you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube, you may be presented with cookies from those websites. The University of Ulster does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the relevant third party website for more information about these.

Where video is used on the University of Ulster website, users are able to watch the video via the embedded flash based player.

**What if I opt out?**  
You will no longer be able to view/play embedded YouTube videos on the University of Ulster website

[The YouTube privacy policy](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/policies/privacy/). 

Top

* * *

**Links to external sites**

Our website contains links to other websites. Cookies placed on your machine by these websites are out of the University’s control.

Top

* * *

**How to manage your cookies**

To find out how to manage what cookies you allow, see your browser's help section below or your mobile phone manual.  

Top

* * *

**Security**

We employ security measures to protect your information from access by unauthorised persons and against unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction or damage.

Top

* * *

**Changes to this Privacy Statement**

We may amend this statement from time to time. If we make any substantial changes we will notify you by posting a prominent notice on our website.

Top

* * *

**Third Party Links**

Our website may, from time to time, contain links to the websites of third parties. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to third party websites that we may link to.

Top

* * *

**Contact us**

If you have any queries concerning privacy, your personal information or any questions regarding our use of the information then please contact [webmaster@ulster.ac.uk](mailto:webmaster@ulster.ac.uk).

Top

Revised: 27 September 2012
